okay shall we get started yeah so I'll
好吧，我们开始吧，所以我会
just close the door
刚关上门
they're coming be quick we have 30
他们很快就会来30
seconds or 10 seconds sorry sorry okay
秒或10秒对不起对不起
so let's get started so welcome to from
所以让我们开始吧，欢迎来自
Java EE to Jakarta session my name is
Java EE至Jakarta会话我的名字是
Dmitry Kornilov I am so I need to read
Dmitry Kornilov我是，所以我需要阅读
because I remember Who am I really a
因为我记得我真的是谁
software development manager at Oracle I
Oracle I的软件开发经理
am also a poor J pmc member representing
我还是可怜的J pmc成员
Oracle in Ipoh JP MC I am also leading
甲骨文在怡保JP MC我也领导
quite a few project I begin headed owner
我开始担任项目负责人
Jason binding candy ass son Jason
杰森绑糖果屁股儿子杰森
processing and eclipse link here down
处理和日食链接在这里
there and don't know why it was moved to
在那里，不知道为什么被搬到
the line it was perfect then last time I
这条线是完美的，然后上次我
checked it my blog add my twitter handle
检查它我的博客添加我的推特句柄
feel free to follow me and before I
随时跟随我，在我之前
actually start I have to show that this
实际开始，我必须证明这一点
is safe harbor statement we kind of
是我们的安全港声明
legate to put this slide into slide
放下这张幻灯片
decks it's illegal staff say that what
甲板上，非法人员说
I'm going to talk about it's not
我要说的不是
necessary be a part of the final product
必须成为最终产品的一部分
so you should not make your critical
所以你不应该批评
business decisions based on that
基于此的商业决策
of what I'm going to talk about today
今天我要谈论的
I'm talk about today the achievement and
我今天说的是成就
rewards to this achievement and I will
奖励这项成就，我会
try to explain what had to be done in
尝试解释必须做什么
order to achieve it right and the
为了实现它正确和
achievement is eclipsed GlassFish 5.1
成就使GlassFish 5.1黯然失色
rc1 release it was announced yesterday
昨天宣布的rc1版本
and you can check it out them to be an
你可以检查出他们是一个
honor maven central if you go to that
荣誉行者中央，如果你去那
link it's a public key a publicly
公开链接它是公共密钥
available now also I wrote a relatively
现在可用，我也写了一个相对
small article explained how did they do
小文章解释了他们是怎么做的
it
它
and how big is it and what kind of
它有多大？
challenges they had basically my talk is
他们遇到的挑战基本上是我的谈话
based on that article the link to the
根据该文章的链接
article is there so when I publish my
文章在那里，所以当我发布我的
slides after its session you'll be able
会议结束后滑动，您将能够
to see it and we couldn't do it without
看到它，我们离不开它
help so it's not only Oracle who does
帮助，所以不仅仅是Oracle
it's not only clips foundation how it
它不仅剪辑基础如何
does it so I would like to say thanks
这样做，所以我想说谢谢
and thanks to our local teams practing
还要感谢我们当地的团队
IDC team US team thanks to your Clips
IDC团队美国团队感谢您的剪辑
foundation thanks to Wayne thanks to
基金会感谢韦恩感谢
Tonya thanks to Sharon and all their IP
Tonya感谢Sharon及其所有IP
team and of course thanks to get masters
团队，当然要感谢掌握大师
forever out there butters we stuck at
永远在那里我们停在黄油
the beginning and thanks to all vendors
开始并感谢所有供应商
who participated in building GlassFish
谁参与了GlassFish的建设
and all the related work so thanks to
和所有相关的工作，所以感谢
IBM
IBM公司
thanks to your Red Hat thanks to Pereira
多亏了你的红帽，多亏了佩雷拉
Tommy tribe and all others this is the
汤米部落和所有其他部落
achievement and how it started and
成就及其开始方式和
started from one idea from the last Java
从上一个Java的一个想法开始
one about a year ago
一个大约一年前
so I think it's almost exactly here we
所以我认为这几乎就是我们
go is it not more or less so all you
难道不是或多或少，所以你们
possibly seen this slide so it was in
可能看过这张幻灯片，所以它在
really many slide decks right so it's
真的有很多滑轨，所以
all about that we announced that Java EE
关于所有这些，我们宣布Java EE
will be transferred to eclipse
将被转移到日食
foundation and this is the Oracle part
基础，这是Oracle的一部分
and unity and vendors will provide
和团结，供应商将提供
sponsorship and we will build a new
赞助，我们将建立一个新的
platform that time it wasn't Jakarta he
那时不是雅加达平台
was not named store name came rather and
没有命名商店名称来了，
this platform supposed to be nimble
这个平台应该是敏捷的
flexible open compatible I would add
灵活开放兼容我会添加
else or normative render independent and
其他或规范使独立
this kind of stuff so this is the final
这种东西，所以这是最后的
goal and you see that we actually
目标，您会看到我们实际上
released GlassFish from eclipse so we
从eclipse发布了GlassFish，所以我们
not finally it's not a final release but
最终不是最终版本，但
they are very close in achieving this
他们在实现这一目标方面非常接近
goal and Oracle is going to transfer
目标，甲骨文将转移
things so what exactly what exact
事情到底是什么
difference our Java EE what is Java what
区别我们的Java EE什么是Java什么
exactly is transferred okay
完全可以转移
specifications
规格
api's our eyes TCK TCK is very important
api是我们的眼睛TCK TCK非常重要
because it was not open earlier so no
因为它没有早点打开所以没有
one has seen that what is TCK right
有人看到什么是TCK对的
everybody knew that t ck are there but
每个人都知道那里有
no one actually seen t ck so and
实际上没有人见过
everybody wanted TCK TCK is very
每个人都想TCK TCK很
important here and also some satellite
在这里很重要，还有一些卫星
stuff like manuals documentation samples
手册手册样本之类的东西
websites and this kind of stuff so this
网站和这类东西，所以这
is basically the package what we are
基本上就是我们的包
transferring to eclipse same
转移到日食相同
transferring what press reports about
转移新闻报道的内容
finished yet
还没完成
and how big is it so we are saying he
它有多大，所以我们说他
eyes our eyes but how big is it
看着我们的眼睛，但它有多大
it can be small right on the keynote mic
在主题麦克风上可能很小
already spoiled some numbers and it's
已经破坏了一些数字，这是
from my blog article it's ok so Java EE
从我的博客文章中可以，所以Java EE
right 5.5 million lines big number and
550万行
2.2 million lights of comments so you
220万条评论灯，让您
see that we actually comment in quite a
看到我们实际上在相当长的一段评论中
lot API it's must be well commented
很多API，必须对此进行评论
right and it's in 61k files Oh quite a
对，它的文件大小为61k
lot of files as well and CTS and TC
很多文件以及CTS和TC
cases what no one's seen before 4.6
4.6之前没人见过
million lights of course
万盏灯
so you see it's comparable with Java EE
所以您看到它与Java EE相当
Co right so TCK testing Street just a
正确，所以TCK测试街只是一个
little bit not little bit million lines
几百万行
of code less than Java EE right and it
代码少于Java EE的权利，并且
has 1.1 million lights of comments so
有110万条评论灯，所以
you already can mention that ok so it's
你已经可以提到，好吧
easy case are not commented much
简单的情况没有太多评论
comparing to Java in equal right and it
与Java的平等权利相比，它
34k files or you also can say that where
34k文件，或者您也可以说
every file size is bigger then Java EE
每个文件的大小都比Java EE大
by outside right
在外面右边
so in total we have 13.5 million lines
总共有1350万行
of code in 95 thousand files this is the
9.5万个文件中的代码集，这是
overall size of the contribution the
捐款总额
codebase now you may ask ok 30 min or
现在，您可以要求确定代码库30分钟或
half million lights of god and I can't
五百万的上帝之光，我不能
realize really what is that so I
真正意识到那是什么，所以我
collected some information for
收集了一些信息
comparison here
比较这里
so the full contribution size java ee +
因此，全额缴款额java ee +
TCK look it's slightly more than the
TCK看起来比
firefox codebase I can't say which
火狐代码库，我不能说哪个
version of my report they say current
他们说我的报告版本
but maybe we collected this data some
但也许我们收集了一些数据
time ago so
以前这样
just Firefox right and Java EE codebase
只是Firefox和Java EE代码库
is comparable with World of Warcraft's
可与《魔兽世界》媲美
your website conveys who is playing
您的网站传达了谁在玩
World of Warcraft okay I expected that
魔兽世界好吧，我希望
which is why I have a second comparison
这就是为什么我要进行第二次比较
Linux kernel to 6-4 it's quite an old
Linux内核为6-4，这已经是很老了
version of Linux kernel but at least you
版本的Linux内核，但至少您
can imagine how big is it right TC case
可以想象TC案例有多大
itself comparable with Windows ends in T
本身可与Windows相提并论
3.1 codebase again this is quite old and
3.1代码库再次相当老
this is why I have a second comparison
这就是为什么我要进行第二次比较
Photoshop cs6 it's also old but not so
Photoshop CS6也很旧，但不是这样
August Windows NT right so we have a
8月的Windows NT对，所以我们有一个
test speed which is comparable with
测试速度与
Windows NT codebase so which is the
Windows NT代码库，这是
operating system this is quite amazing
操作系统，这非常了不起
is it so now we understand that which is
现在知道了吗
really huge contribution to this by the
对此的巨大贡献
way all these data taken from this
所有这些数据的方式
information is beautiful dotnet if you
信息就是美丽的互联网
go there we have it slightly nicer
去那里，我们稍微好一点
presented and you see a lot more code
呈现，您会看到更多代码
base sizes you can play with it quite
基本尺寸，您可以轻松使用
amazing actually
真的很棒
so now I realize how big is the
所以现在我意识到
contribution and now I'll talk about how
贡献，现在我将讨论如何
it was contributed there is a process
它被贡献有一个过程
for contribution here it is I had many
为了这里的贡献，我有很多
questions and community had a lot of
问题和社区有很多
questions why take so long it's Oracle
问题，为什么要花这么长时间才是甲骨文
Oracle slow right and you guys are not
甲骨文放慢脚步，你们不是
doing anything you just get I had one
做任何事情你都会得到我一个
comment really pretty funny the guy said
这个人说的评论真的很有趣
you know that where is the possibility
你知道可能性在哪里
on github to change the ownership of
在github上更改的所有权
repositories cool so
仓库很酷
I would go that way really
我真的会那样走
but we have process and we have lawyers
但是我们有程序，有律师
and we have architects so everything's
我们有建筑师，所以一切
supposed to be done the proper rate just
应该以正确的速度完成
taking time so here is the process and
需要时间，所以这是过程，
left side is basically Java EE Oracle
左侧基本上是Java EE Oracle
side and right side is Jakarta II this
右边和右边是雅加达二世
is the Eclipse IDE and the process
是Eclipse IDE和流程
starts actually funny enough it's on
实际上开始很有趣
Eclipse IDE so we needed to create
Eclipse IDE，因此我们需要创建
project because the clips foundation
项目，因为剪辑基础
operates project and Oracle Java EE we
经营项目和Oracle Java EE，我们
operate repositories so you may say that
操作存储库，所以您可能会说
okay it's more or less the same it's not
好吧，或多或少都是一样的，不是
really because a project is slightly
真的是因为一个项目
bigger than the repository
比仓库大
it has key meters and more important
它具有关键的仪表，更重要
because a project lead which repository
因为项目负责哪个存储库
doesn't have we have about hundred
没有我们有大约一百
repositories and at the end we decided
存储库，最后我们决定
to create a bar 39 project we have 39
创建一个酒吧39项目，我们有39
projects now and kevin remembers how
现在进行项目，凯文（Kevin）记得如何
difficult was splitting the repositories
很难拆分存储库
between projects because some people
项目之间，因为有人
said ok we would like to have it highly
说，好的，我们希望拥有它
granular and other people said no we
颗粒状，其他人说不，我们
don't want to have it because it's
不想拥有它，因为
complicated right so at the end the
复杂的权利，所以最后
decision was made to have project for
决定有项目
each API definitely we would like to
我们绝对希望每个API
have a project for that and we combine
为此有一个项目，我们结合
some repositories for our writers metro
一些我们的作家的仓库
right
对
it has about 5 6 repositories combined
它总共有大约5 6个存储库
in one project we have juggs be awry
在一个项目中，我们无法做到
again it's combined from remember before
再次结合之前的记忆
file repositories are definitely there
文件存储库肯定在那里
and GlassFish itself is more than 10
而GlassFish本身超过10个
repositories right so you see that from
正确的存储库，以便您从
Hanbridge we had 39 project ok so we
Hanbridge我们有39个项目，所以我们
kind of solved what repositories of
解决了什么存储库
in the project another challenge was
在该项目中，另一个挑战是
naming okay this problem sounds really
命名还可以，这个问题听起来真的很
easy okay so what's the name and you
容易好吧，那你叫什么名字
just get jax-rs nice name so you have
只要给jax-rs取一个好名字就可以了
jax-rs if eclipse doesn't work because
jax-rs如果eclipse不起作用，因为
we have legal we have trademarks and we
我们有法律，我们有商标，我们
really can't use Java name in the
真的不能在
project so if jax-rs start with Java
因此，如果jax-rs以Java开头
right j/a from Java so it's not possible
从Java正确的j / a，所以不可能
to use it so how to name it then because
使用它，然后如何命名它，因为
jax-rs api it's just great name right so
jax-rs api这只是个好名字，所以
this we were discussing it quite a lot
这个我们讨论了很多
finally we found a way that we will call
终于我们找到了一种我们称之为的方式
all API project using the pattern
使用模式的所有API项目
Eclipse project for name of API to
Eclipse项目的API名称
eclipse project for JSONP it leaves
离开的JSONP Eclipse项目
project for jax-rs nice enough for
jax-rs的项目足够好
implementations it was a little bit
实施有点
easier so we decided that we will just
比较容易，所以我们决定我们将
add eclipse before the name of
在名称之前添加eclipse
implementation like eclipse Jersey
像eclipse Jersey这样的实现
sounds good lip search area nice so this
嘴唇搜索区域听起来不错，所以这
is how the naming was salt
命名方式是盐
another challenge committers and leaders
挑战者和领导者的另一个挑战
great so we kinda had committers for a
太好了，所以我们有点提交者
github repository in Java EE right but
Java EE中的github存储库正确但是
it doesn't really mean that these people
并不是说这些人
are working on that project right so a
正在该项目上工作，所以一个
lot of people have rights to this
很多人对此都有权利
project but do we want to add hundred
项目，但我们要添加一百
people from Oracle and bond from IBM and
来自Oracle的人员以及来自IBM和
to from Red Hat for instance doesn't
例如，从Red Hat迁移到
sound good so we had a discussion who to
听起来不错，所以我们讨论了谁
put into the project finally it was
最后投入到项目中
resolved so we've came out with a list
解决了，所以我们列出了一个清单
of committers for each project and we
每个项目的提交者数量，我们
also solved who to put to the lead right
也解决了谁来领导
because we want to spread leaders
因为我们想传播领导者
between all organizations we would love
我们希望的所有组织之间
to have some leaders from community
有一些社区领袖
again we solved it I think successfully
再次，我们成功解决了
so it leaks somehow it works for now and
所以它以某种方式泄漏了
the final bit here just to create a
最后一点只是创建一个
project proposal which after that
项目建议书
becomes then goes through community
然后成为社区
review I think as the executive board
作为执行委员会，我认为
review becomes a project but it takes
审查成为一个项目，但这需要
time it's not like you submit a proposal
时间不像您提交提案
now and tomorrow we have a project
现在和明天我们有一个项目
created it takes about three weeks if I
如果我创建大约需要三个星期
remember well so it partially are
记得很好，所以部分是
already answered the question why take
已经回答了为什么要服用的问题
so much time right okay so this is what
好多时间好吧，这就是
happens to the clips and in parallel in
发生在剪辑中并在
parallel we started to prepare codebase
并行，我们开始准备代码库
remember code based concrete
记住基于代码的具体
repositories 13 million lines of code
仓库1300万行代码
for contribution and the important thing
为了贡献和重要的事情
here are reduced IP review and court our
这是减少的知识产权审查，并向我们求婚
preview so basically Oracle needs to
预览，因此基本上Oracle需要
approve court that you guys can give it
批准法院你们可以给它
away techniques and eclipse should say
遥远的技术和日食应该说
okay we are except in this code so this
好的，我们不在此代码中，所以这
is two important things then both of
是两件重要的事
them are passed we find right so we
他们通过了，我们找到正确的，所以我们
asked the clips
问剪辑
what kind of scanning tools are you
您使用哪种扫描工具
using so we set okay so we use it and
使用，所以我们设置没问题，所以我们使用它，
have soldier and we use your code scan
有士兵，我们使用您的代码扫描
took it great so we took the same tools
很棒，所以我们采用了相同的工具
and ran a run it on on our repositories
并在我们的存储库上运行它
just to simplify work to eclipse and we
只是为了简化工作，我们
found many things there many challenging
发现很多东西很多挑战
things which we had to source our
我们必须采购我们的东西
headers like lights and skater sign
标头，如灯和溜冰者标志
correct wrong curl lights and sticks
纠正错误的卷曲灯和棍棒
defiles dependencies which are strange
file毁奇怪的依赖关系
and this kind of stuff so we solved that
这类东西，所以我们解决了
and after that we have two rules
然后有两个规则
Oracle legal approval it means that we
Oracle的法律批准意味着我们
submit code to our legal department we
将代码提交给我们的法律部门
check the licenses when check like this
像这样检查时检查许可证
for all dependencies and they may say
对于所有依赖关系，他们可能会说
that okay you know
好的，你知道
dependency doesn't work license is wrong
依赖不起作用许可证错误
hey folks you have to change it to
大家好，您必须将其更改为
something else can you imagine that we
你还能想像我们
have a project which works and we need
有一个可行的项目，我们需要
to change one dependence to something
改变一种依赖
else
其他
sometimes it's okay if it's dependency
有时候如果有依赖关系就可以了
in the tests or in samples it's fine to
在测试或样品中可以
remove the sample right but if it's in
删除样本权，但如果在其中
the cold it becomes challenging too what
寒冷也变得充满挑战
should we do right so we need to find
我们应该做对吗，所以我们需要找到
solution to that and then it's salt it
解决方案，然后加盐
goes to corporate architecture and the
去企业架构和
Veii can say the same thing you know
Veii可以说出你所知道的同一句话
fault
故障
so these dependency is old come on Java
所以这些依赖关系来自Java
is all right some project there are born
好的，有些项目诞生了
10 years old so it's obvious that like
10岁，很明显
dependencies they're old right but okay
依赖关系，他们是老权利，但还可以
you need to uptake some later your beta
您需要稍后再使用Beta
latest latest version of dependency
最新最新版本的依赖
great but new version sometimes
很棒，但有时会有新版本
backwards compatible sometimes we are
向后兼容有时我们是
not backwards compatible sometimes they
有时不向后兼容
say that it's better prepared about in
说它在准备更好
real they are not backwards compatible
真正的他们不向后兼容
right so we had to deal with this kind
对，所以我们不得不处理这种情况
of challenges so basically get to latest
挑战，因此基本上可以了解最新情况
if your original run all the tests make
如果您原本运行所有测试，
sure everything works and so on and this
确保一切正常，依此类推
is on hundred repositories and 13.5
在一百个存储库和13.5上
million slice of god right easy I don't
万片神对，我不容易
think so I know it's not right okay
想，所以我知道这是不对的
when this step is done will last to list
完成此步骤后，将最后列出
it here quite easy so we are releasing
这很容易，所以我们要发布
the last version from Oracle repository
Oracle存储库中的最新版本
okay and we are communicating with
好的，我们正在与
community that repository is closed so
该存储库已关闭的社区，因此
we are putting the warning message so
我们在发出警告信息
this is the closet repository you just
这只是你的壁橱仓库
go to eclipse so if some developer
蚀，所以如果有一些开发商
didn't know that my moving stuff to
不知道我搬来的东西
eclipse and you know quite a lot of
日食，你知道很多
errors we did not so we go to the
错误，我们没有，所以我们去
repository
资料库
oh it's archive so what's going on Chari
哦，这是存档，所以Chari发生了什么
is no more Wow how is it a move to
不再哇怎么走
eclipse
日食
oh okay right we communicated on mailing
哦，好的，我们通过邮件进行了交流
lists we communicated on groups dot io
我们在点io上交流的列表
forums that we are transferring projects
我们正在转移项目的论坛
to you
给你
Eclipse again sometimes it's not enough
Eclipse有时还不够
sometimes people just don't see this you
有时候人们只是看不到你
know P people have some kind of limited
知道P人有某种局限性
you know visual abilities or they see
你知道视觉能力或他们看到
depository receipt Oracle's I don't read
存托凭证Oracle的我不读
anything well on Twitter Java is no more
Twitter上的一切都好了J​​ava
okay come on
好吧，来吧
but I hope that by doing that we filter
但我希望这样做可以过滤
it a lot of this kind of thanks okay so
非常感谢，所以
after we've done all of that we can
完成所有这些操作后，我们可以
actually do the initial contribution
实际做初始贡献
what does it mean it means that we
这意味着什么，我们
submitting a special request to Eclipse
向Eclipse提交特殊请求
Foundation saying that and attaching the
基金会说，并附上
zip file with contribution they're
带有贡献的zip文件
saying this is what we are going to give
说这就是我们要给的
you please check it and IP team
你请和IP团队核对一下
basically Sharon and your team are doing
基本上沙龙和您的团队正在做
a quick check and in the most cases it
快速检查，在大多数情况下
was fine because we deal with Oracle and
很好，因为我们与Oracle打交道，
it was a CLE but sometimes we needed to
这是一个CLE，但有时我们需要
change something there but we really
在那里改变一些东西，但是我们真的
wasn't minor things so this is fast
不是小事，所以很快
because it's kind of fast track so it
因为这是一条快速通道，所以
Clips checks it it looks okay they say
剪辑检查它看起来还可以，他们说
okay now just submit the sources to the
好吧，现在只需将来源提交给
source code repo and we will continue
源代码回购，我们将继续
the background check so we're full check
后台检查，所以我们进行了全面检查
isn't in progress and during this full
正在进行中
check we need to submit C cues for every
检查，我们需要为每个提交C线索
single project dependency 13 dot 1/2
单个项目依赖项13点1/2
million lines of code 100 repositories
百万行代码100存储库
where a quite a lot of dependencies so
这里有很多依赖
for each of them we need to submit CQ we
对于他们每个人，我们需要提交CQ我们
do the same thing Oracle we need to do
做我们需要做的Oracle同一件事
it again if eclipse this is ok this
如果日食再次可以
whole process was I'm not saying I'm not
整个过程是我不是说我不是
blaming Eclipse that it's bad
责怪Eclipse这是不好的
which is fine to do and this is actually
做的很好，这实际上是
needed to do right it's just another
需要做正确的事情，这只是另一个
step to do so this somehow goes in the
这样做的步骤
background so we submitted sources
背景，所以我们提交了资源
checks goals we submit in seek use
检查我们在寻求使用中提交的目标
another thing here is see ICD pipelines
另一件事是看到ICD管道
I'm going to touch it a little bit later
我稍后再碰
I have a special slide for that by ICD
我有一张ICD的特别幻灯片
pipelines are needed it's because we can
需要管道是因为我们可以
release artifacts only from eclipse
仅从Eclipse中释放工件
Jenkins why it's like that it's because
詹金斯为什么会这样，因为
it whiskey for security reasons in OSS
出于安全考虑，在OSS中使用威士忌
our age the artifacts are deployed exist
我们时代的人为因素存在
one account per Eclipse project so
每个Eclipse项目一个帐户，因此
jax-rs has an account in OSS RH Gaston
jax-rs在OSS RH Gaston中拥有一个帐户
has accountant or SSH only one account
拥有会计或SSH仅一个帐户
and we are asking rights to the target
我们在要求对目标的权利
groups for this account so we're not
对该帐户进行分组，因此我们不是
giving our ssh account to all committees
向所有委员会提供我们的ssh帐户
because committees are changing right we
因为委员会正在改变我们
just do it for one account and Jenkins
只需为一个帐户和詹金斯做
pipeline Eclipse change Kings we give
我们给的管道Eclipse Change Kings
access to that only two key meters and
只能访问两个关键仪表
job itself has access to that
工作本身可以访问
credentials to OSS our age but this
我们年龄的OSS凭证，但这
credential z'ha'dum
z'ha'dum凭证
so developer can't see them right oh
所以开发人员看不到它们哦
this is not what we usually do right
这不是我们通常做的正确的事情
this is fine to do but this is not per
这样做很好，但这不是每个
usually do it's not what we used to so
通常不是我们过去那样
an Oracle will also have Jenkins stores
一个甲骨文也将有詹金斯商店
we also have pipelines we have jobs we
我们还有管道我们有工作
have released jobs you get build jobs
发布了工作，您获得了工作
but we are not doing it this way but it
但我们不是这样做，而是
slightly differently right so this is
略有不同，所以这是
why it's a bit complicated to get used
为什么习惯起来有点复杂
to this new environment and get used to
适应这个新环境并习惯
how to build these new jobs other thing
如何建立这些新工作
here is it's cloud Jenkins
这就是詹金斯的云
infrastructure which we particular in
我们特别关注的基础设施
Oracle with we never use it right
我们永远不会正确使用Oracle
it's a little bit different than normal
这与正常情况有些不同
gently speak IBM you're not using that
轻轻地说IBM，您不使用那个
that's alright the Red Hat do you use
没关系，您使用Red Hat吗
cloud Jenkins no you use it just normal
云詹金斯不，你用它只是正常的
or you don't use Jenkins at all maybe
或者你根本不使用詹金斯
anyway so I think all of us it's it was
无论如何，我想我们所有人都是
new for all of us right so that's like
对我们所有人来说都是新的，就像
another small obstacle that we need to
我们需要的另一个小障碍
get used to it another obstacle here
习惯这里的另一个障碍
that Eclipse provided us this kind of
Eclipse为我们提供了这种
clean environment and we actually
干净的环境，我们实际上
require quite a lot of things to add it
需要很多东西来添加它
there all right so we needed to when you
没事，所以我们需要当你
took up Java there sometimes multiple
占用了Java，有时多个
versions we need to have made them there
我们需要使它们在那里的版本
we need to have maven plugins there so
我们需要在那里有Maven插件
sorry Jenkins plugins doing something
抱歉，Jenkins插件正在做某事
there so it's not really empty
那里不是真的很空
environment with what we need right and
我们需要的环境正确
it's our first project so I think then
这是我们的第一个项目，所以我认为
when we started aging projects there it
当我们开始在那里老化项目时
became easier because we already know
变得更容易，因为我们已经知道
and masses already know what we might
群众已经知道我们可能
ask for but at the beginning we didn't
要求，但一开始我们没有
know and we had to request one by one
知道，我们不得不一一要求
okay we need Java okay this is Java now
好的，我们需要Java好的，现在是Java
we need to mail them okay maybe this
我们需要邮寄给他们好吧，也许这
year okay so it's a bit slow see I see
一年还好，所以有点慢
the tasks are not finished yet but we
任务还没有完成，但是我们
are very close to finish them so
非常接近完成它们，所以
hopefully next Monday we have updated
希望下周一我们更新了
deadline for C ICD pipelines on next
C ICD管道的下一个截止日期
Monday so this is where we are now we
星期一，所以这就是我们现在的位置
are building C ICD pipelines and after
正在建立C ICD管道，之后
it's done another step is release review
完成了另一步是发布审核
according to eclipse development process
根据日食发展过程
we can't release public artifact unless
除非发布我们的产品，否则我们无法发布
it's approved by the city and before we
它是由城市批准的，然后我们
release review before actually apply for
在实际申请之前发布审核
a list view all background shaking tasks
列表查看所有后台摇动任务
which I was mentioning initial
我最初提到的是
contribution supposed to be done right
应该做的正确的贡献
so basically review so you can be
所以基本上回顾一下，这样你就可以
initiated only the
仅发起
Eclipse IP team finishes all this work
Eclipse IP团队完成了所有这些工作
right and we are really busy now we are
对，现在我们真的很忙
doing really well but can you imagine
做得很好，但你能想象
that suddenly we received so many
突然间我们收到了很多
projects and we need to process them
项目，我们需要处理它们
really fast so we're a busy now and for
真的很快，所以我们现在很忙
some projects IP check are completed I
我完成了一些项目的IP检查
know that was some project that become
知道那是一些成为
project the process is still in progress
项目过程仍在进行中
and after that artifact can be released
然后那个神器可以被释放
publicly okay how long I spend describe
公开好吗我花了多长时间描述
in the process 20 minutes right so this
在20分钟的过程中，所以这
is only description of the progress in
仅描述进度
real it takes months and we need to do
真的需要几个月，我们需要做
it for every single repository we
对于我们每个单独的存储库
transfer so mobile hungry repositories
转移移动饥饿的存储库
right and the fusion don't have I'll
正确，融合没有我
keep repeating that I kind of like this
继续重复我有点像这样
number all right
没事
stretching and a half million lines of
伸展了五百万行
code right so every single line goes
代码正确，因此每一行
through this process
通过这个过程
cool okay and this is how actually
很好，这实际上是这样
projects appeared at eclipse its
项目出现在日食
timeline start in December last year and
时间轴从去年12月开始，
now we are at October so you see that
现在我们在十月，所以你看到
two projects first to project the peer
两个项目首先要对等
that eclipse is just on an eclipse link
蚀只是在蚀链接上
first to project easy project because
首先要设计简单的项目，因为
actually they were already at eclipse
实际上他们已经在日食
they didn't go through all this
他们没有经历所有这一切
complicated process it was exactly like
复杂的过程就像
change in the parent project project
更改父项目项目
leaps RT now it's e4j so but anyway
飞跃RT现在是e4j，但无论如何
tours two projects are their first real
游览两个项目是他们的第一个真实项目
projects which went through all this
经历了所有这些的项目
process are actually that Jase this
过程实际上就是Jase这个
JSONP JMS we have socket open mq we're
JSONP JMS我们有套接字打开mq
also jax-rs and tires GRC was also in
jax-rs和轮胎GRC也在
the first batch but it appeared at
第一批但出现在
eclipse only there in April because
只在四月食
George is huge right so it was the first
乔治是对的，所以这是第一个
batch all this process
批处理所有此过程
after that we're actually we have five
在那之后我们实际上有五个
batches right and now we are working on
分批处理，现在我们正在努力
batch number five and bench number five
第五批和第五批
is actually documentation websites and
实际上是文档网站，
these kind of things what is not really
这些事情不是真的
needed for GlassFish build so you see
GlassFish构建所需，所以您会看到
that we were working quite hard and it
我们在努力工作，
was continuous we only had like July
是连续的，我们只喜欢七月
summer time we contributed only
夏季，我们只贡献了
management API that month we huge batch
那个月我们大量管理API
was in September where we actually
在九月份，我们实际上
transferred GlassFish when withers floor
枯萎时转移了GlassFish
TCK 4.1 million lines of code
TCK 410万行代码
contributed and permissive license batch
批量许可的许可证
permissive license means that we are
许可许可证意味着我们
using EPL to license for everything
使用EPL许可所有内容
except some projects which share code
除了一些共享代码的项目
base with JDK right so it's juggs be
JDK的基础是正确的，所以很难
jax-ws sage these projects are
jax-ws sage这些项目是
contributed and moved under egl lightest
在egl最轻的时候做出了贡献并感动
which is basically bsd so but timeline
这基本上是bsd，但时间表
continues because budget batch 5 is not
继续，因为预算批次5不是
there hopefully soon we will move
希望很快我们会搬到那里
everything ok so we talked about how big
一切正常，所以我们谈到了有多大
was a contribution how complicated is
贡献是多么复杂
the progress process and now we'll talk
进展过程，现在我们来谈谈
a little bit about participation 5
关于参与的一点5
minutes so how community participates
分钟，以便社区参与
then who is participating there so I
那是谁参加
counted around 80 active committers what
大约有80位活跃的提交者
is active committer I thought that okay
是活跃的提交者，我认为还可以
so if person just have one contribution
所以如果一个人只有一份贡献
he's not active right so I decided then
他不是很活跃，所以我决定
I was collecting this data that active
我正在收集活跃的数据
committer is a person who did some more
提交者是做更多事情的人
than five contributions and contribution
超过五个贡献和贡献
it can be submitting a bar can be commit
它可以提交一个酒吧可以提交
can miss the meeting APR so this kind of
可能会错过会议APR，所以这种
you understand what I mean right so we
你明白我的意思对，所以我们
have 80 people who contributed more than
有80个人贡献超过
five things and we have mobile freaking
五件事，我们有移动怪胎
with not active contributors so
没有积极的贡献者，所以
submitted like one buck report or one
提交一份或一份报告
commit right detective I don't think so
犯正确的侦探我不这么认为
but these people they we have free
但是这些人他们有自由
carbon this canopy and all were to
碳这顶篷，所有的人
coverage deseeded committers what does
覆盖去种子的提交者做什么
it mean it means that committees
这意味着这意味着委员会
assigned to the project so on the paper
分配给项目，因此在纸上
they are rare I think some of them are
他们很少，我想其中一些是
really active but some of them are not
真的很活跃，但其中一些却没有
doing anything but just list it as
什么都做，只是将其列为
project committers we have to Congress
我们必须向国会提交的项目提交者
to them we have more than thousand
他们有超过一千
commits in the new project contributed
致力于新项目的贡献
to eclipse yes they are run the script
蚀是的，他们正在运行脚本
so it showed me some hundreds 1100
所以给我看了几百个1100
something and we have about 900 PRS
什么，我们大约有900 PRS
actually customized if it's number so
实际上是定制的（如果是数字）
quite big you know that we have quite
很大，你知道我们有
close number of peers number of commits
关闭点数提交数
because we try to be open and we it's
因为我们努力做到开放，这是
kind of bad practice to do direct
做直接的坏习惯
commits we usually require a PR so
提交我们通常需要PR，因此
community see what actually we're
社区看看我们实际上是什么
committing so bees like these numbers
像这样的数字犯蜜蜂
are close and I have a couple of
很近，我有几个
diagrams or first diagram is committers
图或第一个图是提交者
by organization I'm talking about this
通过组织我正在谈论这个
on the paper committers right so I took
在纸质提交者上，所以我接受了
all committers data probably clips and
所有提交者的数据可能都是剪辑和
created this kind of beautiful pie chart
创造了这种美丽的饼图
so you see that Oracle is still very big
所以您会看到Oracle仍然很大
at large at logic means that we could
从逻辑上讲，这意味着我们可以
identify organization of a committer
确认提交者的组织
can be community member individual
可以是社区成员个人
committer can be that organization is
提交者可以是该组织是
not listed in his profile iBM is also
没有在他的个人资料中列出iBM也是
big after that red head trauma try
大红头外伤后尝试
Fujitsu / Yarra the apt IPO tell Google
富士通/雅拉首次公开募股告诉谷歌
from Google didn't know that Tmax all
来自Google的人不知道所有的Tmax
right so this is how it looks now
对，所以这就是现在的样子
does it look good I don't really think
看起来不错，我真的不认为
so because we really would love to have
所以，因为我们真的很想拥有
these sectors more or less equal for
这些部门或多或少等于
each organization right we want we don't
我们想要的每个组织，我们都不会
want to have then a very some majority
想要拥有多数
like Oracle our committers right so this
像甲骨文一样，我们的提交者是正确的，所以这
is not the point
不是重点
I hope that in a year and a couple of
我希望在一年之内
years we have more participation from
多年来，我们有更多的参与
others and this chart will be like with
其他人，这个图表将与
chapters will be more or less equal
章节将大致相等
another chart similar but leads by
另一个相似的图表，但由
organization again I will she break IRA
我会再次组织她打破IRA
same picture we have Oracle which is
我们拥有Oracle的同一张图片
about 40% I would say and after that we
我会说大约40％，然后我们
have para and I think it's because of
有段，我认为是因为
rei on organ is great we have Tommy
管风琴很棒，我们有汤米
tribe IBM Red Hat and others again
部落IBM Red Hat和其他人
basically we have the same picture and
基本上，我们有相同的图片，
my vision is it would be much nicer each
我的愿景是每个会更好
sectors are have a same square that's a
部门有一个相同的正方形
goal ok not much time I promised to talk
目标还可以，我答应过的时间不多
a little bit about CGI CD pipelines
关于CGI CD管道的一些知识
I'll try to be quick this is the stat so
我会尽快说明这是统计信息
we use in Jenkins cloud infrastructure
我们在Jenkins云基础架构中使用
there is allele I am tracking status of
我正在追踪等位基因状态
jobs using github boards you can check
您可以使用github板检查作业
it here and this is the status from
这是这里的状态
yesterday 94 done 20 in progress want to
昨天94正在进行20想
do I believe I checked today there is
我相信我今天检查过吗
much less about 16 or 18 in progress now
现在少了约16或18
so yesterday some tasks were closed
所以昨天有些任务关闭了
which is great so we are really coming
很棒，所以我们真的来了
to the point that next week we may
到下周我们可能
finish with zero tasks cool so currently
完成零任务很酷，所以目前
build pipelines are finished for 35
建造管线完成35条
projects out of 39 and release pipelines
在39个项目中发布并发布管道
finished for 24 projects are for 39
完成了24个项目，完成了39个
which is perfect it's finished for
完美的完成了
almost 80 for all API
所有API差不多80
it means if they can come to the next
这意味着如果他们可以来下一个
step and next step would be actually up
步骤和下一步实际上是向上
taking new version of api's and releases
采用新版本的api和发行版
them to the staging
他们到舞台上
next step would be up taking all of that
下一步将采取所有这些
in implementations and after that we can
在实施中，之后我们可以
test build GlassFish and the final pink
测试版本GlassFish和最终的粉红色
is release it and this is what listed
发布它，这就是列出的内容
here in the GlassFish 5.1 release plan
在GlassFish 5.1发布计划中
so what's green is done and so far we're
所以绿色完成了，到目前为止
meeting all the deadlines we will see
满足我们将看到的所有截止日期
how out walk in future because it's a
将来怎么走，因为这是一个
community project it's very difficult to
社区项目很难
predict it's very difficult to manage it
预测很难管理
we will see again so far so good
到目前为止我们会再次看到的
five of November we have a very
11月5日，我们有一个非常
interesting deadline which is then
有趣的截止日期
actually projects needs to uptake other
实际上项目需要吸收其他
Eclipse components and be released to
Eclipse组件并发布到
OSS RH release review is planned 30th of
OSS RH版本审核计划于30日
November and 14th of December plant date
工厂日期为11月和12月14日
for the final GlassFish release is it
最终的GlassFish版本是
doable it is doable we will see how it
可行，可行，我们将看看如何
goes because maybe very else will be
去，因为也许还有其他
some obstacles which we don't know maybe
我们可能不知道的一些障碍
community won't be active enough again
社区将不再足够活跃
so far so good and to help us achieving
到目前为止一切顺利，并帮助我们实现
this participate so if you want to help
参加，所以如果你想帮助
us you're welcome
我们不客气
this is the Jakarta website this is the
这是雅加达的网站，这是
mailing list check it out subscribe to
邮件列表签出订阅
it contact project leads if you have to
如果需要，可以联系项目负责人
sit in some particular project ask lead
坐在某个特定的项目问领导
what how how can I help and let's do
我该如何帮助我们
together and that's the last slide thank
在一起，这是最后一张幻灯片，谢谢
you very much and I'm perfectly on time
您非常多，我很准时
if you have any questions time is over
如果您有任何疑问，时间已经过去了
just stop here on catch me somewhere
停在这里捉我
I'll be happy to answer
我很乐意回答